vinepair.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Policy | VinePair

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To customize and optimize the appearance of our website and/or email newsletter.
  * Complete your purchase
  * Facilitate your entry in a survey, contest, or event
  * Share information obtained through web pixels with our service providers and with third parties with whom we contract to share such information for purposes such as tailored advertising (See cookies and web pixels section below)

**How do we protect visitor information?**

We only provide articles and information. We only ask for personal or private information like names, email addresses or credit card numbers in the event you are registering for our newsletter, making a purchase, applying to participate in an event, or other limited circumstances where collection of such information is made clear to you.

We use regular Malware & Security Scanning.

**Do we use ‘cookies’ and web pixels?**

Yes, we use both cookies and web pixels. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. We also use cookies to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. Web pixels are small tags designed to capture overall site information, such as the number of visitors, which areas of our site they visit, and how long they stay on our site. We use web pixels to generate statistics about how our site is used. We do not use web pixels to access any personally identifiable information; rather, web pixels capture aggregated and anonymized analytic information. However, we may share information obtained through web pixels with our service providers and with third parties with whom we contract to share such information for purposes such as tailored advertising through which you may become individually identifiable to such provider or third party.

**We use cookies to:**

  * Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.
  * Keep track of advertisements.

**View Cookie Settings**

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, some features will be disabled.

However, you can still place orders.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information such as aggregate anonymized information collected through cookies and web pixels may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by [Google’s Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en). They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. 

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

**We have implemented the following:**

  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * Demographics and Interests Reporting

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

Opting out:

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting [the Network Advertising initiative opt out pag](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1)e or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing us

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

It’s also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via email

  * Within 7 business days

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.

**To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

  * NOT use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at**

  * Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.

and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

vinepair.com

20 West 22nd St Ste 512  
New York, NY 10010  
US

info@vinepair.com  
646-801-2722  
Last Edited on 2019-04-15
